Yamin Siahmargooei - Software Engineer

• Location: Gorgan, Iran

• Site: https://yamins.ir

 \bullet Email: yamin[dot]siahmargooei[at]gmail[dot]com

• Phone: +98-933-888-0330

• Telegram: https://t.me/yamins

• LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/yaminsm

• Github: https://github.com/yamin8000

• Stackoverflow: Profile Link

Summary

I'm a Computer Engineer specializing in Software Engineering. Skilled in Android App Development and have professional experience in Kotlin and Java. I also have semi-professional knowledge in C, C++, C#, Python, and PHP programming languages. As a Software Engineer, I'm interested in any type of software development; From Embedded programming utilizing AVR/ATmega with C, IoT projects by making use of Raspberry Pi/Arduino, Back-End projects using the Ktor framework, and mostly Android projects which are my main area of expertise.

Experience

• Freelance Software Engineer

Self-Employed

Sep 2020 - Present

I developed multiple Android applications using Kotlin/Java (Compose/Views) and published them in Appstores such as F-Droid and CafeBazaar also I published an Android library in Maven Repository

• Software Engineer

Aryan Spad

Sep 2020 - November 2023, 3 yrs and 3 mos

During my time at the company I developed some Android applications for contractors and helped in development of an Email Queue program using Kotlin and Ktor framework and I was also part of team that helped developing multiple websites using Laravel and Wordpress

Gap year

Career Break Dec 2018 - Sep 2020, 1 yr 10 mos Mandatory Military Service • IoT Apprentice

Golestan University

 $\rm Dec~2017$ - Aug $2018,~9~\rm mos$

Worked on a project developing a platform for devices in IoT using Raspberry Pi as a Gateway

• Technical Support Specialist

Xperian.ir

 $\operatorname{Jan}\ 2014\ \text{-}\ \operatorname{Feb}\ 2017,\ 3\ \operatorname{yrs}\ 2\ \operatorname{mos}$

Technical Support and content creation

Education

• Golestan University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Engineering Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

Software Engineering

Thesis: Implementation of the server and gateway application based on the client-server model in the framework of a Internet of Things network

Skills

• Programming Languages

- Kotlin Professional
- Java Professional
- SQL Intermediate
- − C# Intermediate
- PHP Basic
- Python Basic
- C/C++ Basic
- Rust Basic
- 8086 Assembly Basic

• Industry Knowledge

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Android Development
- $\ \mathrm{Git/GitHub/Gitlab}$
- Data Structures
- Refactoring
- Regular Expressions
- Internet of Things (IoT)
- Raspberry Pi
- AVR/ATmega

• Tools and Technologies

- Android Studio
- IntelliJ IDEA
- Visual Studio
- SQL Server
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Material Design

Language

English - Full professional proficiency,

Persian - Native or bilingual proficiency